好了吗   好了
Ready? Yeah.Okay.
嗨  这是瑞秋  和菲比的家
Hi. it's... Rachel. and...Phoebe's.
请  哔
Please. Leave.
在哔声后
Leave.
在哔声后  那个我说过了
But I just said "leave."
我知道  因为你都分到好的字
Yeah, I know, because you have all the good words.
而我呢  "这是"  "和"  还有"留言"  我不要
What do I get? I get "it’s," "and" oh I'm sorry, I have "A." Forget it.
菲比  别闹了  好  那我们交换
Phoebe, that's silly. All right. So let's switch.
不要   我都分到好的字
No, I have all the good words.
好吧  我们交换
Okay, fine, fine. We can switch.
好  好啊
okay. okay
嗨  大家好
Hi. Everybody.
这是  瑞秋
It's. Rachel.
和  菲比的家
And. Phoebe's.
请慢着  你是怎么弄的
Pleas-Wait. How did you do that?
什么
What?
你不是普通角色   对吧
Oh, you're no ordinary roommate, are you?
菲比  待会再录好吗  我想在天黑前去慢跑
Phoebe, come on, can we finish this later? I wanna go running before it gets dark.
你也一起来跑嘛  真的
Why don't you come with me? Really?
对   一定很好玩的
Yeah, oh, it'll be fun.
去公园跑步  当做室友间第一次联络感情
We'll run in the park. It'll be like our first, you know, roommate-bonding thing.
好  我们去跑步
Okay, let's go running!
而且  那里还有帅哥  那我们就朝那边跑
Yeah, and there's cute guys there. Let's run towards them!
好
0Kay.
你等我一下
Wait just one more second.
嗨  这是瑞秋和菲比的家   请在哔声后留言  谢谢
Hi, it's Phoebe and Rachel's. Please leave a message. Thanks!
等等  你都讲完了
Now, wait a minute. You just took all the words.
你遇到对手了  瑞秋葛林
Uh-huh. You've met your match, Rachel Green.
老友记  第六季  第7集  菲比跑步
Friends  S06E07  The One Where Phoebe Runs
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
我刚看完一本很棒的书
So I just finished this fascinating book. Hmm.
到了2030年  有些电脑
By the year 2030, there'll be computers...
能执行跟人脑一样多的命令
...that can carry out the same amount of functions as an actual human brain.
所以  理论上  你可以把思想记忆
So, theoretically, you could download...
下载到这种电脑上
...your thoughts and memories into this computer...
然后以机器的形态长生不老
...and live forever as a machine.
我刚发现我能睁着眼睛睡觉
And I just realized I can sleep with my eyes open.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
把箱子钉在地上真是聪明
Honey, it was a great idea, nailing the boxes to the floor.
我没把箱子钉在地上   所以你可以搬走了
I didn't nail the boxes to the floor. Oh, so you can move them.
可以  我这就搬   罗斯有个很好听的电脑故事
Yes, and while I'm doing that, Ross has a great computer story for you.
嘿  大家好   这是吉宁
Hey, everybody. Uh, I'd like you to meet Janine.
她是我的新室友
She's gonna be my new roommate.
你好
Hi. Hi.
她要来跟我住
And she's gonna live with me!
很高兴认识你  吉宁
It's nice to meet you. Janine...?
勒夸  吉宁勒夸
Lecroix. Janine Lecroix.
我都不知道  好好听的姓啊
I didn't know that. What a pretty last name.
你是哪里人
So, uh, where are you from?
澳洲人  两星期前刚到
Australia. I just moved here a couple of weeks ago.
来自于南半球  对
From the land down under? Yeah.
这个我也不知道
I didn't know that either.
你做哪一行
So, what do you do?
我是个舞者  你是个舞者
I'm a dancer. You're a dancer?
她是个舞者
She's a dancer.
我要去整理东西了  我帮你开门
Well, I think I'll go and unpack. Here, let me--
乔伊   在
Joey? Yeah?
你叫她搬来之前有先面试过吗
Did you even interview this woman before you asked her to move in?
有  当然有啊
Of course I did. Uh-huh.
你到底问了些什么
What exactly did you ask her?
你什么时候可以搬来
When can you move in?
谢谢你把她带到我们身边
Thank you for bringing her into our lives.
好个大美人
Unbelievable.
你也喜欢她  钱德
Oh. Oh, so you like her too, Chandler?
你看这堆箱子
Hey, look at all the boxes.
我好想赶快约她
I cannot wait to ask her out.
等等  乔伊  乔伊  你不能约她
Wait a minute, Joey. Joey, you can't ask her out.
她是你的室友  那样的话太复杂了
She's your roommate. It'll be way too complicated.
没错  千万不要
Yeah, man, don't do it.
你约了她   我就不能约她了
I mean, if you date her, then I can't date her.
你之前跟一个叫唐娜的交往  后来分手了
Think about it. Remember when you were going out with Donna and you broke up...
记得你们在超市巧遇的尴尬吗
...remember how horrible it was when you bumped into her at the supermarket?
没错
Oh, God, yeah.
想像你住在超市里
Now imagine you live at the supermarket.
好啊
0Kay.
不   不   不是
No, no. Oh. Oh.
你说得对   那样很不好   我不能约她
You're right. I don't want that. I can't date her.
最好也别跟她调情  住得这么近
And you'd better watch the flirting too, because in close quarters...
太可怕了  可能会出事
...it could be trouble. Well, that's gonna be tough, Mon.
太难了  毕竟美女当前   我很难不打情骂俏
I mean, it's hard for me to be around an attractive woman and not flirt.
我老是在你面前  你也没怎样么
Heh. Well, you're around me all the time, and you don't flirt.
有点难过  是吧
A little sad about that, sweetie?
我要绑鞋带  你先跑  我就来
I have to tie my shoes, so you go ahead. I'll catch up.
好  好
Okay. Okay.
拜托   那哪叫跑步啊   快点
Come on, that's not running. Let's go!
（中央咖啡厅）
我是说真的  她跑步的时候
You guys, I'm telling you, when she runs...
就像大嘴蛙
...she looks like a cross between Kermit the Frog...
和生化机器人合体
...and the Six Million Dollar Man.
摩妮卡以前好喜欢他
Monica had such a crush on him. Ha, ha.
她睡觉之前都会亲他的海报
She used to kiss his poster every night before she went to bed.
我也会
I used to do that too.
你有他的专辑 《全身绿色的烦恼》吗
Oh,my God. Did you also have his album, It's Not Easy Being Green?
摩妮卡
Oh, Mon.
所以菲比的姿势很怪
So Phoebe runs weird, huh?
对  而且她还想再去跑
Yeah. And you know what? And I know she's gonna want to run again.
我跟她住在一起  躲不掉
I don't know how to get out of it. I mean, I live with her.
你就实话实说嘛
Why don't you just be straight with her? Tell her the truth.
你说得对  我应该跟她直说
You're right. You're right. I should just tell her the truth.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
菲比  摩妮卡把我绊倒了   我再也不能跑步了
Hey, Pheebs, Monica tripped me. I don't think I can ever run again, ever.
为什么  你为什么要绊倒她
Why? Why would you do that?
我不知道
I don't know.
瑞秋  抱歉害你两个脚踝受伤
Rachel, I'm sorry that I hurt your ankles.
只有一个  等着瞧
Ankle. We'll see.
好  东西都拿出来了
Okay. I am officially unpacked.
多谢帮忙
Thanks for helping me, man.
乔伊
JOe?
看来他回家了
Well, I guess Joey went home.
看  还有一个箱子没拆
Oh, and look, there is still one box that I have to unpack.
你被骗了
I got you.
天哪  我差点被吓出心脏病
Oh, my God, you almost gave me a heart attack.
我想笑想得好辛苦
It was so hard not to laugh, I'll tell you.
很像一回事嘛
Hey, the place looks great.
不赖吧
Yeah, not bad, right?
摩妮卡今天要加班   我要把这里打扫得一尘不染
You know what? Monica's working late, so I'm gonna make this place spotless.
还有  还有
You know what else I'm gonna do?
我还要下楼去  买花送她
I'm gonna go downstairs, I'm gonna get her some flowers.
谁不想跟我住
Now, who would not want to live with me?
我不想
I don't.
我想跟性感的澳洲舞者住
No, I want to live with the super-hot Australian dancer.
情况如何  你能不打情骂俏吗
How's that going, though? Are you okay with the not-flirting thing?
目前  还可以  但是好累啊
Yeah, so far. Yeah. But it's tough, you know?
我的调情能量一直在累积  无处发泄
I've got all this built-up flirting energy, and I don't know how to get rid of it.
你好吗
How you doing?
天哪
Oh, man.
抱歉   客厅比较宽
Sorry. There's just more room out here.
不   不是  我只是想到  我也该拉拉筋了
Oh, no, no, you just, uh, reminded me that I have to do my stretches too.
你应该
Why don't you try to be...? Aah!
怎么了  没事
What's wrong? Uh, nothing.
你不要碰我
I just-I didn't want you to touch me...
我拉筋拉得全身都是汗
...because I'm all sweaty from the workout. Ha, ha.
我去洗个澡
I'm gonna hit the shower.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
抱歉在浴室晾衣服
Oh, sorry about that stuff hanging in there.
我的丁字裤很娇贵  不能烘干
It's just my thongs are too delicate for the dryer.
啊嗯
Aah! Hi.
没错  是我
Oh, yeah, uh-huh, it's me.
我看到你抄着慢跑鞋就溜出来了
I saw you grab your running shoes this morning and sneak out.
你骗我   好自己跑步
You lied so you could run by yourself.
不是  菲比  我没有  我是
No, Phoebe, no. I was-No.
我只是跑跑看看
I was actually just checking...
看看我
...to see...
能不能跑   结果还可以
...if I could run. And I can.
拜托  瑞秋  我又不是白痴
Please, Rachel, I'm not an idiot.
不  等等  菲比
No, wait. Phoebe?
同居真的会让人越来越像
Wow. Couples who live together do start to look alike.
摩德
So, Mondler...
嗯
Uh...
你在干什么
What, uh--? What are you doing?
你说呢  我在打扫
What does it look like? I am cleaning.
你动她的东西有经过她同意吗
Did you get Monica's authorization to move all of her stuff?
同意  没必要吧  我会把东西都放回去
Authorizat. I don't need that. I'm gonna put everything back.
完全恢复原状吗
Put it back exactly where you found it?
当然是  完全恢复原状
Yes. I'm gonna put it back exactly where I found it.
这种态度对你没有帮助
Okay, first of all, that attitude is not helping.
她才不会在乎有没有恢复原状
She won't care if I put her stuff back in the same stupid place.
你是刚认识摩妮卡吗
Hello? Did you just meet Monica?
她会认同我的体贴的
She's gonna recognize that I did a nice thing...
而且会感到贴心
...and appreciate it.
其实  这样也蛮好的
Huh. No, actually, this will work out well.
等你必须搬回去跟乔伊住
Because when you have to move back with Joey...
乔伊热辣的新室友就可以跟我来住
...Joey's hot new roommate can come live with me.
我懂了  你想吓我
Oh, I see, I see. You're trying to freak me out.
钱德  摩妮卡对这种事有怪癖
Look, Chandler, Monica is really weird about this kind of stuff, all right?
相信我  我跟她住了16年  她会捉狂的
Believe me, I lived with her for 16 years. She's going to freak out.
天哪  她会压在你身上
Oh, my God. She's going to sit on you.
她才不会  好吧   我证明给你看
No, she is not, okay? I'll prove it to you.
我现在就打给她
I'm gonna call her right now.
电话擦好了
Phone's done.
摩妮卡  你好吗
Hi. Hey, Mon. How's it going?
烂透了  什么事都得我自己来
Terrible. If I want something done right, I have to do it myself.
其他人只会搞砸
Other people just wreck stuff.
我今晚可能会杀人
I really think I might kill someone tonight.
别这样  没那么糟吧
Oh, come on, come on, it can't be that bad.
是非常的糟  想到快见到你了
It's worse. The only thing getting me through...
我才撑得下去
...is knowing I'm gonna see you soon.
我搞不好会设法早退  不  不要
I might get out of here early. No. No, no, no.
不  不  餐厅似乎很需要你
No, no, it sounds like they need you there.
你跟罗斯在一起吗  一切都很好  再见
You're just hanging outwith Ross? It's all good. Okay, bye, Mon.
她会宰了我
She's gonna kill me.
电话放反了
The phone was facing the other way.
相框应该摆在上面
And that goes back up there.
知道怎么搞嘛  我们从大型家俱复原开始
Know what we should do? We should start with the big stuff.
会比较简单  先搬沙发
That'll be the easiest. So, uh, let's start with the couch.
我没问题
I got it.
位置好像不对
Yeah, that doesn't look right.
什么意思  沙发刚好跟毯子对齐
What are you talking about? The couch is perfectly in line with the carpet.
我可以走到这边  轻松的把脚翘在
Then I can just walk over here and casually just put my feet right up on...
好  就这样
Okay, here's what we do.
那就把沙发往茶几那边推
We just move the couch closer to the coffee table.
那沙发的背后  就不会跟毯子边缘对齐了
But then the back of the couch won't line up with the back of the carpet.
那就把茶几往
Okay, well, here, we'll just, uh, move the coffee table...
沙发那边推
...closer to the couch.
不  那茶几就不在座位区正中央了
No, whoa, whoa! But then the coffee table won't be centered in the seating area.
那茶几就配不上桌子了  罗斯
But the coffee table doesn't match the table-Ross.
我该怎么办
Hi. Look, what am I gonna do?
我不调情  但还像火吸引着飞蛾一样吸引着她
I'm not flirting, but still I'm drawing her to me like a moth to a flame.
这里是怎么了
What the hell's going on over here?
摩妮卡会宰了你
Monica's gonna kill you.
我需要你们的帮忙
Look, I need your help, okay?
我得想办法把这个女人吓跑
I have to do something to repel this woman.
等等   等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你们最会把女人吓跑了
You guys repel women all the time.
我可是结过三次婚
Hey, I've been married three times.
不  不  我亲眼见识过
No, no, no, I've seen it happen.
你们跟女人开始都交往得好好的   最后还是都搞砸
You get a rapport going with a woman, but somehow you manage to kill it.
你们的秘诀是什么
What's your secret?
我们不会把女人吓跑
Look, we do not repel women,
完全没有这么回事
Okay? That is completely untrue.
不过  我们确实会
Oh, yes, we do, my man.
记不记得  大学参加春季舞会
Remember back in college when we went to that dance...
你瞄上了那个女生  走过去却不停地大谈
...and you walked right up to that girl you liked and couldn't stop talking...
爱尔兰的马铃薯饥荒
...about the Irish potato famine?
那你呢  当年也没那么酷
Yeah, well, what about you? You weren't so hot in college either.
他每次说完话  都会加叭噜锵砰
After everything he said, he'd go:
摩妮卡也不喜欢  也许我应该改掉
Yeah, Monica doesn't like that either. Maybe I should stop doing that.
对了  女生都不喜欢我聊科学
You know what? Girls don't like it when I start talking about science.
不止是女生
That's not specific to girls.
太好了  还有呢
This is great. This is great. What else?
她们不喜欢你纠正她们的文法
They don't like you correcting their grammar.
她们不喜欢你解释你的笑话哪里好笑
And they don't like it when you explain why your jokes are funny.
她们不喜欢你一直问她们   喜不喜欢你
You know, they don't like it when you keep asking them if they like you.
天哪  幸好我有摩妮卡  我再也别想谈恋爱了
Man, I am so lucky I have Monica. I'm never gonna find love again.
嘿
Hey
菲比  可以跟你谈谈吗  好啊
Phoebe, can I talk to you for a second? Sure.
好  我
Okay. Um, I--
菲比  我只是想跟你道歉
Phoebe, look, I just wanted to say that I'm sorry, okay?
我不擅长处理这类事情
I handled the situation horribly.
而且我不该骗你
And I should not have lied to you.
那你应该怎样
So what should you have done?
我应该跟你说实话
Well, I should have told you the truth.
就是
Uh-huh. Which is?
我之所以不想跟你跑步
Well, you know, the reason that I didn't want to go running with you is...
是因为
...because, urn...
你跑步的姿势有点
...well, you know, the way that you run is just a little...
所以呢   很尴尬
So? Well, it's embarrassing.
别人都当我们是疯子
People were looking at us like we were crazy.
你干嘛在意呢   因为他们是人
Why do you care? Because they're people.
你既不认识  也不会再见到的人
But people that you don't know and will never see again.
但他们依旧是人
Yes, but still they are people...
有眼睛
...with eyes.
我就不怕
Well, I didn't get embarrassed running next to Miss:
跟喘气小姐跑步
Choo, choo, choo, choo.
但是  好吧
But, oh, okay.
难怪你会觉得跟我跑步很尴尬
No, no, I can see why running with me would be embarrassing to you.
是啊  你完全放不开
Yeah, okay. You're uptight.
什么  我哪有放不开啊
What? I am not uptight. Whoa.
我才不会放不开  老兄
Listen, I am not uptight, man.
没关系  瑞秋  我不是在批评你  你就是这样的
That's okay, Rachel. I'm not judging you. That's just who you are.
对  我就比较自由  从小就是这样跑
Me, I'm more free, you know? I run like I did when I was a kid...
因为这样才好玩
...because that's the only way it's fun, you know?
你从来没有往前冲到腿好像快要断了吗
I mean, didn't you ever run so fast you thought your legs would fall off...
例如要跑去玩荡秋千
...you know, like, when you were running towards the swings...
或是玩在躲魔鬼时
...or running away from Satan?
邻居的狗
The neighbor's dog.
这盏灯没摆错吧
Okay, is this lamp in the right place?
管他的  我会把女人吓跑
Who cares? I repel women.
不  不行  你不能进来
No, no, no! You can't come in here.
罗斯光着身子的
Ross is naked!
什么  什么
What? What?
我不能说我光着身子   她可以看我光着身子
I couldn't say that I was naked, because she's allowed to see me naked.
为什么一定要有人光着身子
Why does anyone have to be naked?
罗斯为什么光着身子
Why is Ross naked?
我要给钱德看一个东西
I had to show Chandler something.
光着身体看
Naked?
对
Yeah, I uh...
我好像有
I guess I have, a, uh...
男人病
A guy problem.
跟钱德的一样吗
Is it the same thing that Chandler had?
待会儿再回来
Look, just come back later.
我们搞定了  你再回来
We'll get everything squared away, and you can come back later.
好吧
Okay. Hey, listen.
浴室洗手台底下  还有钱德的药
There's still some of Chandler's medicine left under the sink in the bathroom.
再见  再见
Bye. Bye.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你有什么病
Dude, what'd you have?
没时间了  我们必须专心
Look, we have no time, okay? We must focus.
要把一切都恢复原状
We've got to get everything back into its original place.
相册
The photo album.
相册里一定有一大堆这里的照片
There were millions of pictures of the apartment in the photo album.
我们可以拿来对比
We just go through it and match everything to the pictures.
太好了  好主意
That's perfect. That's brilliant. Yeah.
说真的  你有什么病
So really, what did you have?
乔伊  我帮你买了啤酒
Hey, Joey. I've got some beer for you.
是 "帮谁"吧
Uh, don't you mean "for whom"?
好
Sure.
我正想叫彼萨  你要一起吃吗
Listen, I was gonna order some pizza. You wanna share one?
披萨  我又不是没吃过  叭噜砰锵
Pizza? It's not like I never had that before.
有什么问题吗
Is there something wrong?
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
我就明说了
Let's just get this out in the open, okay?
你很火辣
You're hot.
我很俊俏
I'm lovable.
显然  我们两个很有感觉
Clearly, there's a vibe going on between us.
但我们是室友
But we're roommates...
我们不能走上这条路
...and it's a huge mistake for us to continue down this road.
乔伊  不  我是说真的
Joey-No, no, no. I'm telling you.
想像你住在超市里  这样你就懂了
Imagine yourself living in a supermarket and you'll understand.
好吧  所以  我们该怎么办
Okay? So the question is, what do we do?
不怎么办
Well, I don't think there is anything to do.
我觉得你人很好
I mean, I think you're really sweet.
但是我对你没兴趣
But I'm just not interested in you like that.
嗯
Oh.
不是
No, I mean...
你人真的很好  我很高兴能当你的室友和朋友
You're a really nice guy, and I'm happy to be your roommate and your friend.
只是  我对你
I'm just, you know, I just...
没有那种感觉
...don't feel that way about you.
嗯
Oh.
我知道了
I see what happened. Ha, ha.
因为我一直想把你吓跑
It's because I was trying to repel you.
真的  相信我   一旦我放电  情况就大不同了
Right? Believe me, you'd feel a lot different if I turned it on.
应该不会   绝对会
I don't think so. Oh, I do.
你好吗
How you doing?
我很好
I'm okay.
什么
What?
怎么了
我的天哪
Oh, dear God.
嘿   嘿
Hey! Hi!
对不起  你说得对  感觉好爽
I'm so sorry. You're right. This feels great.
对吧  你不要在意别人的目光
See? And you don't care if people are staring.
才几秒钟  你就跑不见了
It's just for a second, because then you're gone.
没错  感觉真的好棒  菲比  我觉得好自由好优雅
It's amazing, Pheebs. I feel so free and so graceful.
嗯
Oh!
嘿   小心那匹马
Ha! Hey, look out for the horse.
抱歉
Sorry.
我可以进去了吗
Is it okay for me to come in now?
嗯
Uh-huh.
为什么东西都变了  再见
Why is everything different? Bye.
没有变啊
I don't see anything different...
只不过你一进来  房里变得更亮了
...other than the fact that the room got so much brighter when you came into it.
小茶几位置不对  沙发怪怪的
Well, the end table is wrong, the couch looks bizarre...
更别提冰箱上的磁铁了
...and don't even get me started on the refrigerator magnets.
你别生气
Okay, look, don't be mad, okay?
我整理完东西  想做点让你高兴的事
But after I unpacked the boxes, I wanted to do something nice for you...
所以我就大扫除了
...so I cleaned the apartment.
我把东西乱搬  却忘了
So I moved everything around, and then I forgot...
该怎么复原  对不起  对不起
...where it went back. And I'm sorry, I'm very sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
没关系
That's okay.
钱德   你在怕我吗
Chandler, are you afraid of me or something?
你要我怕你吗
Do you want me to be afraid of you?
当然不要
Of course not.
拜托   钱德  你做了这么棒的事
My gosh, Chandler, what you did is a wonderful thing...
我真的很开心
...and I really appreciate it.
我知道我对东西的摆设有怪癖
I know I have this thing where I want everything in the perfect place.
但我万万没想到  你会担心
But I'd never expect you to worry about that.
真的
Really?
当然是真的
Of course.
你最好了
Oh, you're the best.
过来我抱抱
You come here to me.
等等  先做该做的事
Hold on, okay? First things first.
那个
Okay. Now...
罗斯光着身子时坐过哪里
Did Ross sit anywhere while he was naked?
书上说到了2030年
So it said that by the year 2030...
有些电脑能执行跟人脑
...there will be computers carrying out the same number of functions...
一样多的指令
...as an actual human brain.
所以理论上   人可以把思想记忆
So theoretically, you could download your thoughts...
下载到这种电脑上
...and your memories into this computer--
然后以机器的形态长生不老
And live forever as a machine.
吉宁  你知道我们现在在做什么吗
Uh, so, Janine, do you know what we're doing right now?
我们在连结
You and I, we're interfacing.
我该走了
Yeah. I gotta go.
叭噜砰锵